All right! Here.
Here you go. Careful!
Hold on. All right!
Lord Hayate,
thanks to you, Gon and his men will be taken
to the royal capital's prison camp,
and our transport team will
be able to set out safely.
As someone who serves the kingdom,
I have only fulfilled my
duties as expected of me.
I trust that sincere, earnest nature of yours,
and so I have a favor to ask of you.
If it's something within my capabilities...
This letter is for your
esteemed father, Lord Gouki.
If you could pass it to him, for me...
To my father?
It is a very important letter.
If you could give it to him personally,
I would greatly appreciate it.
I understand.
I must go to the next village
for their tax evaluation,
so I won't return to the royal
capital until after that,
but I will, without fail.
Will that be acceptable?
You have my thanks.
Stay safe!
And so, we all...
traveled together, and parted
with Lord Hayate along the way.
Kingdom of Karasuki, Royal Capital
We didn't reach the royal capital of the
Karasuki Kingdom until several days later.
Seirei Gensouki
Royal Lineage
This is where we'll be staying.
If you get lost, you won't
be able to make it back,
so when you leave the premises, make sure
to go with someone who knows the capital.
I've got to go out, so I'll
leave the rest to you.
Rio, Shin, will you come with me?
Yes.
Me, too?
Come on.
That dirtbag.
I was thinking of killing him.
Not a very satisfying end, is it?
Come on, now.
Don't just sit there looking depressed.
Time for your emotions to change tacks.
C-Cut that out, Huntmaster!
This guy's watching!
Three large servings of kamutan!
Thanks for waiting!
This is kamutan?
Huh? Rio, you've never had kamutan before?
N-No, I haven't.
Once you have, you'll start craving it.
The first time you ate it, it was an
emotional experience, right, Shin?
I suppose...
With kamutan, slurping it up dynamically
is the classy way to do it!
Come on, Rio. If you don't
eat it, it'll get soggy.
I will. Thank you for the meal.
This is delicious!
Right?
Yes!
Thank you!
Hey!
Thanks for what you did for Sayo.
What?
Oh, right.
I need to make sure she gets to eat this,
or else we'll get into another fight.
Is that everything we were needed to get?
Yes. Thank you so much, Sir Rio!
But asking me, someone unused
to the town, to go shopping...
I can't imagine what everyone was thinking.
If you'd like, shall we go
eat some kamutan after this?
What?
Master Shin asked me to take you
if we could manage it, Miss Sayo.
My brother did that?
He said he'd asked you to make it for him,
but you got into a fight, saying you couldn't
make it since you'd never eaten it.
He said he wanted to make sure
you couldn't say that next time.
Honestly, he's such a glutton.
But I think maybe he just wants to give
you the chance to eat some, Miss Sayo.
What?
He's a nice older brother, isn't he?
Yes, he is.
You there, young man!
How about a gift for that
cute girlfriend of yours?
I-I'm not his girlfriend or anything!
Oh, my! You look so
good together, I just assumed.
But how about just one souvenir of the capital?
We have some very nice
wares here, wouldn't you agree?
That's true. Since we're
here and everything...
Miss Sayo, is there anything you want?
What? I-I'm fine!
You've done so much for me,
Miss Sayo. Please, don't hesitate.
Yes, yes.
Miss, at times like these, quietly accepting
the gift shows a lady's courteousness.
Really?
Miss, you're very good
at business, aren't you?
Thanks!
My, miss, what a good eye you have!
That's one of our finest items.
Would you like to try it on?
What?
What do you think, young man?
It really suits you.
Doesn't it? It looks so lovely on you!
But the price is just so high.
It's two lesser silver tablets.
L-Lesser silver tablets?
All right.
S-Sir Rio, it's all right!
I really don't need...
I might be able to give
just a little discount.
I could never haggle over the
price of a gift for a lady.
Very impressive!
In that case, I should have
set the price a little higher.
Shall we go?
Th-Thank you so much!
Young lady!
Do your best to make him yours!
It seems to me there'll be a lot of
competition for that young man.
You ruffian! Unhand me!
Someone, get him!
Outta the way! Outta the way!
What?
Miss Sayo! Are you all right?
Y-Yes, I'm fine.
Lady Komomo!
She seems to be unconscious, but I don't
think there's any risk to her life.
M-My apologies. This is all due
to my hopeless incompetence.
If you're going to apologize,
apologize to her when she wakes.
What happened?
What's going on?
Clear a path!
Let's go, Miss Sayo.
What? But... are you sure?
Yes. I want to avoid any kind of trouble.
Please, wait!
Are you all right?
You're not hurt?
Komomo was almost kidnapped?
We're lucky that they were unsuccessful.
The young man who saved Komomo
and apprehended the perpetrators
quickly departed the scene, they tell me.
So, you said you wanted a private word?
Yes.
Lady Yuba entrusted me
with this for you, Father.
She said that it was an important letter,
and I should give it to you in person.
I see. From Lady Yuba.
Hayate...
Yes?
Did you meet someone named Rio?
We're back!
Hey, good work.
Big Brother, the kamutan was delicious!
Huh?
Then, when we get back to the village,
this time you'll make some for me, right?
Yes. I'll do my best!
Sayo, where did you get that hairpin?
Huh?
Oh, um, well...
I'll go put these away.
Lord Rio!
Lord Hayate?
I am called Saga Gouki.
I am Kayoko.
We are husband and wife, and we
were both once attendants of your mother...
Lady Karasuki Ayame.
Karasuki... Ayame?
Your surprise is understandable.
Lord Rio, your mother was of the royal
family of the Kingdom of Karasuki.
My mother... was royalty?
First, shall I tell you about my
connection to your father Zen, Lord Rio?
Yes.
It happened over twenty years ago.
At the time, the Karasuki Kingdom was at
war with our neighboring kingdom, Rokuren.
Zen volunteered to be a soldier.
Zen had a natural gift for both
the spirit arts and martial arts.
His Majesty the King soon bestowed
upon him the rank of warrior-noble.
At that time, he had a bout with me.
His skills were the real thing.
Because of that,
I strongly recommended that he should
guard members of the royal family.
I am sure you can already guess that the
member of the royal family he guarded...
...was Lady Ayame.
Lady Ayame took a liking to Zen.
And it was at that time that a truce was
negotiated with the Kingdom of Rokuren.
At the ceremony celebrating the truce,
the prince who had come as ambassador
took a liking to Lady Ayame,
and tried to have his attendants abduct her.
Zen kept them from completing their plan,
but the prince resented the fact that
his attendant had been killed.
If the truce were to be finalized,
the prince demanded Zen's execution,
and a political marriage to Lady Ayame.
Even now, the thought of
it makes my blood seethe.
And that's why my mother and
father ran away together?
Yes.
His Majesty the King
arranged for it in secret,
and the two of them left our country.
And so time flowed on, with no
news or contact with them.
But today, I received
correspondence from Lady Yuba.
And having looked upon your honored
countenance, Lord Rio, I am certain.
There can be no doubt that you are their son.
Yes.
Lord Rio, tomorrow, will you
come to the castle?
What?
His Majesty the King and
Her Highness the Queen...
It is my dearest wish that you
and they might meet, Lord Rio.
The two of them... and me?
Please. Please, I beg of you.
All right, I will.
So you are Rio?
I am honored to meet you, Your Majesties.
King Homura, Queen Shizuku, my name is Rio.
This is a meeting with
our darling grandchild.
Would it be possible for you
to be less formal with us?
Yes, please.
If you permit it, then... I will do my best.
First, will you take a seat?
Yes. Thank you.
Rio, you really do look exactly like Ayame.
I feel that it's you, Queen Shizuku,
who looks just like my mother.
My, do you think so?
Rio, will you tell us?
Tell us about Ayame and Zen.
Yes.
To cut straight to the conclusion,
both of them have already died.
It is how they died and how they lived
that we would like to hear.
My father died when I was
too young to know him.
My mother was a kind person
who never stopped smiling.
She never showed me her
grief at my father's death.
We were by no means affluent,
but every day was a happy one.
But when I was five, my mother passed away.
When you were five?
How did Ayame die?
If I tell you the truth, it will
be incredibly painful to hear.
Even so, we want to know.
My mother...
was killed...
right in front of me.
The person who killed her
is a man named Lucius.
Apparently he had worked with
my father as an adventurer.
After my father's death,
he'd helped us in many ways.
But that day...
I'll be back soon. If anyone you
don't know comes, you stay inside.
I will!
Rio, it's me. It's Lucius.
Will you open the door?
In this world, there are demons
who masquerade in human skins.
You're one fact smarter now.
What are you doing, Master Lucius?!
Rio!
What have you done to him?
Let go! Let go right now!
Rio...
Mother...
That is my last memory of my mother.
How could this be...
And how have you lived since then?
When I woke up, I'd been left in the slums.
I stayed there and lived as an orphan.
Though that was only until I was seven.
What happened then?
There was... an incident where
I happened to rescue someone
of importance to the kingdom.
I was allowed to attend an educational
institution run by the kingdom.
In our kingdom,
we have a school for the court nobles
and some of the warrior-nobles, but...
Everyone around me was of similar rank.
That must have been difficult for you.
I was treated a little harshly,
but there were people who treated me well, too.
Thanks to them, I can hold my head high
and say my days there were enjoyable.
I attended that school until I was twelve,
then I set out for this land that my
mother had promised to show me one day.
Ayame made such a promise?
Both you and Ayame must
harbor a deep hatred for us.
I think my mother was grateful to you...
for being able to marry my father.
It would make no sense for me to
hate you in the face of that, would it?
I see.
But Rio...
The man who killed Ayame...
I don't think I can forgive him.
That man is the one person
I will never forgive.
Then, do you hope for revenge?
Once, that was all
I thought about. It kept me alive.
But revenge doesn't create anything.
And my mother wouldn't want it, either.
I've thought those things, too.
Even so, if I ever met that man...
With these hands, I would...
I see.
But you know, Rio...
If you travel the path of revenge,
what you will find is hell.
I know.
You can still turn back.
Will you proceed, even so?
I am determined to proceed, even so.
If it's necessary, I would not
hesitate to dirty my own hands.
Then, I won't stop you.
But before that, I would
like you to spar with Gouki.
With Lord Gouki?
There is no match for Gouki in
any of the surrounding kingdoms.
He is the Karasuki Kingdom's
strongest warrior.
This man named Lucius must be very skilled.
Considering his hideous nature,
he may even have killed Zen.
Don't you think so, Gouki?
I don't want to admit it,
but it is definitely possible.
If you are to one day face Lucius, then you
will require strength, will you not?
I understand.
If he is willing to teach me
the basics, then, yes, please.
Father! Mother! Welcome home!
You're...
Aoi, what is it?
Th-The person you're with is the
one who saved Lady Komomo!
What's this? Is that right?
Oh, I just...
Then we will proceed with combat forms.
Both parties, at the ready.
Begin!
Your potential is frightening.
And to think that in terms of both
physicality and experience,
you haven't yet reached your prime...
Training is the one thing
I've always kept up.
You've done well!
He combines sword work
with weaponless styles.
Impressive!
What?
It can't be... Father is at a disadvantage?
This is thrilling!
Magical energy is gathering around his sword?
F-Father! You can't be thinking of using...
Hidden Skill, First Blade...
Air Slash!
End of match!
The bout goes to Lord Rio!
I've lost this one.
Thank you very much.
I can't believe Father has...
He's incredible.
Impressive.
I had thought to have you train under Gouki,
but I see my solicitude was unnecessary.
Yes.
Not at all. Having this experience before
heading to Beltrum was invaluable.
Thank you for your concern.
We don't have much time left,
but is there anything you wish to ask?
I have a cousin who lives in the
village where I've been staying.
I would like to tell her
about my lineage, but...
Yes. We will trust your judgment in this.
Thank you.
Welcome back!
Huh? Where's Rio?
Miss Ruri, Sir Rio is...
Father, Mother... I can't run anymore.
In order to live, in order
to protect what's precious,
I will accept the ugliness
within me and move forward.
Next Time
Each of Their Decisions
"Each of Their Decisions."
Spirit Chronicles
Exciting Bonus Manga
Oh! A date
with Sir Rio!
It's like
a dream!
By Minazuki Futago
fluffy
Sir Rio,
this date is
so much fun!
tee hee
I'm just
glad you're
happy.
ha ha...
Huh?
Oh!
panic
Yes...
Did I say
all that
out loud?!